This is a random forest, a powerful machine learning algorithm based on decision trees,
and this is tennis, a sport I'm kind of obsessed with.
In this video, I'll build a random
forest, throw at it a bunch of tennis data, and then make it predict tennis much outcomes,
and predict the winner of a big tennis tournament.
And we'll see how it performs.
But first, I need data.
I want a lot of data.
I want every single breakpoint,
every single double serve, every single double fold, I want everything,
throw back hands, throw forehands, throw heights, throw ages, throw that name, throw mom's name,
throw grandma's secret lasagna recipe.
Yeah, I need that stuff too, man, I'm surviving on noodles
over here.
And then I found it, the holy grail of tennis data sets, a file so massive,
so detailed that opening it, crouched my computer, summoned three statisticians and made my axle
back for mercy.
The famous 2008 Wimmelon final between Rafa and Adal and Roger Featherer,
the longest grindstone final of all time, I got it.
Even this one time, this skidbit Rafa and Adal